JITHIN JOSE Python Developer

About Me

I am a self-taught developer who loves to solve problems digitally with top notch technologies. I am specialized in web technologies. I am working to learn new technologies and seize new opportunities as well as develop creative ideas.

Skills

- Problem Solving
- Creativity
- Leadership
- Communication Skills

Technical Skills

HTML

• CSS

Git

Docker

GitHub

MySQL

• SQLite

MongoDB

• SQL

JavaScript

Bootstrap

- Pvthon
- Java
- C/C++
- Django
- Data Science
- Selenium
- Eclipse
- PyCharm
- Sublime
- Spyder
- Jupyter
- MS Office
- Visual Studio Code

Certificates

Wesleyan University-Coursera -2020 Python Programming: A Concise Introduction

Udemy - 2020 A Full Stack Web Developer

Languages

- English
- Malayalam
- Hindi

Work Experience

Full Stack Web Developer - Intern

Konnect2Digital Services | 2022-Present

· Working on e-commerce project as full stack web developer

Freelancing

Self employed | Oct 2021 - present

- Worked as Python Django web developer.
- · coordinated team members as a Lead.

Projects

Find Latitude-longitude

Konnect2Digital Services | 2022-Present

- Languages: Python Django, Selenium, pandas
- Created to find the accurate latitude and longitude from google Maps using user data as CSV.
- Local e-commerce

Academic project(self) | Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

- Languages: Python Django, HTML/CSS/BootStrap, Database: MongoDB
 - Technologies: DataScience, Machine Learning,
- Created to Implement e-commerce in the local shops for local economic growth.
- Shops can also analyze and predict using their data.
- E-Adventure

Academic project(self) | Dec 2020 - Mar 2021

- Languages: Python Django, HTML/CSS/BootStrap, Database: MySQL
- It was created to Book Adventure Sports Activities online.
- Agro

Freelance project | oct 2021 - Dec 2021

- Languages: Python Django, HTML/CSS/BootStrap, Database: SQLite
- It was created to provide Agricultural details for farmers.
- Handwritten-Text

Personal project | Mar 2022 - Jun 2022

- Languages: Python
- Created to convert handwritten data to text.

Lacauired a 90% mark.

Education

2019-2022 3 years	Bachelor of Computer Application University Institute of Technology - Kerala University I acquired a 68 % mark in the degree with specialized in computer application
2017-2019 2 years	Higher Secondary Education Govt. Higher Secondary School - Kerala Board I acquired a 73.5% mark with specialized in Computer Science
2016-2017 1 years	SSLC N.M.H.S.S - Kerala Board of School